A few years ago,
I posted a video
on Film Booth and
I was convinced, this
is it, this one's
going to blow up.
It had some of
the best information I'd
ever shared. It had
deep data, algorithm analysis,
and I spent absolutely
days writing it. And
it bombed on release,
it did awful. But
when I looked at
the retention graph, everyone
dropped off at the
par that I thought
was gold. And that
is when I realised
a painful, but eventually
multi -million dollar lesson.
Because I realised the
way I communicated my
information overwhelmed people and
made it really hard
to follow, so they
left. So with that
in mind, I thought,
well, let's test this.
And I made another
video that did the
exact opposite and it
got 900 ,000 views.
And that's when I
realised the secret to
this. Whether it's YouTube
marketing or email, great
communication always comes down
to just three things.
So in this video,
I'm going to show
you what they are
so you can grow
your channel and your
business in a niche
-leading way. Alright. So
let's start with what
makes a great video
for the business, creating
the content. And that
to me is just
four things. You get
sales, you get emails,
you get views, and
you learn a lesson
so that we can
then take it into
our next video to
make it even better.
Okay, so what makes
a great video for
the viewers? Well, it's
just three things that
will make people go,
how do I work
with this person? And
we can split them
into a triangle. So
the first corner of
the triangle works like
this. So the video
I mentioned earlier. With
900 ,000 views work
because I took something
complicated, which was how
YouTube works. And I
framed it in a
fresh way by comparing
it to a chain
with five links. And
I said, if one
of the links on
this chain breaks, your
whole system is going
to fall apart. Now,
I wasn't saying anything
revolutionary. Creators have talked
about this stuff for
a while. But the
way I presented that
information made it feel
new to people. And
when something feels new,
people pay attention and
new gives people hope
because they think maybe
this time it's going
to click. Maybe this
is the version that
works for me. So
we always need to
work out how can
we make our information
feel new very much
like I'm hopefully doing
for you right now.
Hopefully. All right. So
let's look at the
next corner of an
amazing script. So back
when I made that
super in -depth video,
I thought YouTube was
a game of trying
to show people how
smart you were with
this next level information.
But this is what
makes people comment often.
Get to the point
or this is boring.
Because you confuse it.
You confuse people. And
that wrecks your credibility.
So the real secret
is to make your
viewers feel smart. And
that's what the video
900 ,000 views did
because I took YouTube's
insanely complex system and
broke it down into
five clear parts. And
I used a simple
prop to visually show
this. So the second
corner of the great
content triangle is making
information feel easy to
understand. Not basic, not
dumb, but effortless to
digest, which is very
hard. And then the
final corner of our
triangle. Works like this.
So let me ask
you a question. When
are you more likely
to buy something on
YouTube when a viewer
feels like they understand
something and could actually
do it themselves? It
inspires them to take
the action steps that
you give them. And
if they do that
and they get a
result, they tie that
result to you. Your
credibility goes through the
roof and you get
fans. They will then
come back to everything
you make and enter
your system. And they'll
just be so much
more likely to buy
from you. So the
final corner is to
make your videos inspiring.
So my mission is
to turn you into
someone who can do
all of this. All
of these things in
every video that they
make. But it also
applies to email or
any kind of communication
you do for your
business. Get these three
things right and your
content starts doing the
heavy lifting for you.
All right. So those
are the three cornerstones
of what makes great
content. Now let's just
have a quick look
at what a video
actually is. And it's
only broken up into
three chunks. You have
a beginning, which is
your intro. The middle
is the points that
you want to make
or the lessons or
the steps. It's basically
just chunks of information
that need to feel
new, easy and inspiring.
And then the last
one is the most
important. And then you
have the end, which
is when you tell
them to watch another
video. And that's it.
So move on to
the next video. Now
we're going to look
at the first part
of a video, the
intro. I'm going to
show you how to
turn a thumbnail and
title into an intro
that hooks people to
want to stick around.
So they binge your
videos and fill up
your sales system.